CRISTINA GABRIEL CONSULTANT

CONTACT

702-861-8002

cgabrielwork16@gmail.com

Q United States

https://kristy1620.github.io/

EDUCATION

BACHERLORS OF NEUROSCIENCE

Georgia State University

2016

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE IN DATA SCIENCE

IBM

2019

SKILLS

Python

SQL

Machine Learning

Natural Language Processing (NLP)

AWS

Data Visualization/Analysis

Project Management

Data Wrangling/Cleaning

Statistics

Calculus

SUMMARY

As a data science professional/consultant with over 5 years of experience aiding clients in academia, corporate and government sectors to address their research and innovation requirements.

Analyzing large internal and external datasets to craft tailored solutions which typically consists of detailed reports, workshops, and presentations.

EXPERIENCE

CONSULTANT

Clarivate

2024-Present

- Use advanced data analysis techniques, such as NLP and clustering to create tailored evaluation solutions, generating detailed reports and visualizations that aid decision-making and strategic planning.
- Developed and implemented a Peer Review evaluation process for a funding charity which led to a sustained service deal.
- Training and onboarding of incoming new hires on company internal assets (AWS, EC2, RDS, APIs) and products.

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT

Clarivate

2021 - 2024

- Coordinated the analysis and delivery of citation metrics to the REF, the UK system for assessing research performance.
- Developed/coded a semi-customizable report which was sold more than 20 times and served as a template for similar reports.

DATA ANALYST

Clarivate

2019 - 2021

- Trained classification algorithm that led to a customer-facing project
- Delivered research performance evaluation report to large
 European funder that led to sustained reporting deal.